



Jaquiel Paim

Nationality: Brazilian Gender: Male Phone number: (+351) 911534672

Email address: jaquiel.paim@gmail.com S Skype: jaquiel.paim_2

in LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jaquielpaim/

Website: https://github.com/jaquiel/

• Home: 4050-453 Porto (Portugal)

ABOUT ME

I have 17 years of experience on software development and I have a bachelor's degree in software engineering. During these years I worked with different programming languages, databases, and agile methodologies. I've been working mainly with .NET, .NET Core, C#, SQL Server, MongoDB, Azure, and Azure Functions, more specifically developing REST APIs, always observing best practices such as Design Patterns, S.O.L.I.D. principles, and Dependency Injection, among others.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Backend Engineer (Full Remote)

Yellowipe [02/10/2023 - Current]

City: Porto | Country: Portugal

Working with a client from digital TV/OTT (Over-the-top) and video delivery solutions based in Spain that provide scalable products and services for worldwide telecom and media companies.

My main responsibilities are the development of features to consolidate the VOD (Video on demand) features on a new platform.

Currently, my contributions are focused on developing the process of scanning, parsing, serializing, and consistency of the metadata from media providers to a new platform streaming.

Skills: .NET 8 · C# · Microsoft SQL Server · Scrum · GitHub · AWS · Bash · Docker

Senior Software Engineer (Full Remote)

Devoteam [07/02/2022 - 09/2023]

City: Porto | Country: Portugal

Working with a client from the Home Improvement sector headquartered in France with worldwide operations, focused on enhancing their e-commerce in Portugal.

My main responsibilities were the development of crucial Customer Account features within the client's e-commerce ecosystem including implementing new authentication and authorization features and ensuring the security and proper access to the customer's personal information.

My contributions aided in enhancing the customer authentication and information storage ecosystem, resulting in a safer and more streamlined online shopping experience. Additionally, I integrated with other services such as orders, payments, wishlists, etc.

Through these efforts, it increased end-user confidence in online transactions, thereby improving the conversion rate.

Skills: JSON Web Token (JWT) · OAuth · DDD · Azure DevOps · Azure Functions · Azure · Swagger API · .NET · Scrum · GitHub · MongoDB · C# · Node.js · API REST

Senior Software Engineer

PrimeIT [15/11/2021 - 28/01/2022]

City: Porto | Country: Portugal

I worked on the development of a new BackOffice software for a women's accessories e-commerce that serves approximately 20 European countries.

My main responsibility was to update and implement features in new software, with new architecture and new stack (REST and .NET 6).

I designed and implemented necessary updates in the software, and integrated the system with Salesforce CRM, consuming SOAP services through WCF clients, for improved sales management.

My contributions led to a more robust and efficient BackOffice software.

Skills: DDD · Azure DevOps · .NET · Microsoft SQL Server · Scrum · Oracle · GitHub · C# · API REST · WCF Services · SOAP

Software Engineer (Full Remote)

AzimuteMed [03/11/2020 – 31/10/2021]

City: São Paulo | Country: Brazil | Website: https://azimute.med.br/english/

Within the context of the Pharmaceutical Industry, I worked on the development of software focused on Specialty and Primary Care products, Patient Support Programs, and Diagnostic Programs.

I developed and maintained tailored software solutions to provide valuable services to medical professionals, patients, and the Pharmaceutical Industry.

My main responsibilities were the creation and maintenance of specialized software, dedicated to specialty and primary care products, which I worked in backend and frontend roles.

These software solutions have made a significant contribution to the Pharmaceutical Industry, enhancing patient care and diagnosis for medical professionals, resulting in a stronger connection between the industry, physicians, and patients.

Skills: React · Azure DevOps · Azure · .NET · Microsoft SQL Server · Scrum · JavaScript · GitHub · MongoDB · C# · API REST · Transact-SQL · .NET Core

Software Engineer (Full Remote)

Advanced Iteam [17/01/2020 – 25/07/2020]

City: São Paulo | Country: Brazil | Website: www.iteam.inf.br

I worked on software that provides the digital process in the justice system, in one of the largest Lawyertechs in Latin America.

My responsibilities were working on new features and maintenance of software in one of the segments of this solution implemented for the Law Courts, which promotes integration among the participants in the judicial process, being them citizens, public or private entities.

I solved problems, fixed bugs, and migrated legacy software from SOA and N-tier to new architecture using REST API's and Microservices.

Skills: React · Microsoft SQL Server · Scrum · Delphi · Oracle · PL/SQL · GitHub · C# · API REST · Transact-SQL · .NET Core · N-tier · Service-Oriented Architecture (SOA)

Software Engineer

Agriness [08/09/2016 - 03/01/2020]

City: Florianópolis | Country: Brazil | Website: https://www.agriness.com

I worked on production management software for pig farms, developed by the company.

My responsibilities in this project were developing new features and maintaining the software, bug fixing, and automated tests.

I helped to maintain the quality of the software and also keep it in the top 1 of similar products, serving 80% of customers in the sector.

Skills: Delphi · MySQL · Oracle · Firebird · DUnit

Software Engineer

Self-Employed [30/03/2015 – 26/08/2016]

City: Greater Porto Alegre | Country: Brazil

I worked as a Self-Employed in two projects.

The first one is financial recovery assistance software, in which I helped the client maintain, fix, and develop tailored features

The second, an event registration software. A project developed from scratch to control the accreditation of exhibitors and visitors at a multisector fair.

Skills: .NET · Microsoft SQL Server · Delphi · MySQL · PHP · JavaScript · C# · Transact-SQL

Software Engineer

Softforce Soluções em TI [12/04/2013 – 26/03/2015]

City: Porto Alegre | Country: Brazil

I worked on-site in a client which is an insurance company, more precisely in insurance and loan management software.

My responsibilities were to help to maintain the internal software applications and solve problems.

I used the ITIL methodology, and I contributed with end-user support for detailing needs, resolution of incidents, problems, and changes, bug fixes, and identification of problems in internal solutions, like Web Apps, and SOAP web services, among others.

As a result, I contributed to maintaining the internal company software ecosystem.

Skills: .NET Framework · Microsoft SQL Server · Scrum · ITIL · Delphi · XML · C# · Transact-SQL · SOAP · WCF Services · Service-Oriented Architecture (SOA)

Software Engineer

Cigam Software Corporativo [01/01/2013 - 14/04/2013]

City: Novo Hamburgo | Country: Brazil | Website: https://www.cigam.com.br/

I worked on developing the company's main product, which is ERP (Enterprise Resource Planning) software.

My responsibilities were the development of new software features specifically in the tax module, where I helped to provide the software always updated with the constant tax changes.

Skills: Microsoft SQL Server · Oracle · PL/SQL · XML · C# · Transact-SQL

Software Engineer

Self-Employed [01/06/2012 – 31/12/2012]

City: Novo Hamburgo | Country: Brazil

I worked as a Self-Employed to provide software development services to an SME (flower shop).

My responsibilities in this project were to design customized solutions for the business, where I developed software that was provided to manage the customers, orders, billing, and deliveries of the shop.

The software features helped to improve business management.

Skills: Delphi · Firebird

Software Engineer

Naphta Informática [02/01/2010 – 31/05/2012]

City: Novo Hamburgo | Country: Brazil | Website: http://www.naphta.com.br/

I worked on developing the company's main product, which is ERP (Enterprise Resource Planning) software.

My responsibilities were to maintain the software and develop new features.

I contributed to developing features for all ERP modules, mainly for the electronic invoices which was the main module of the software and I helped to deliver to the customers through the ERP essential features and customized solutions when needed.

Skills: Scrum · Delphi · XML · Firebird

Software Engineer

Self-Employed [01/06/2009 – 31/12/2009]

City: Novo Hamburgo | Country: Brazil

I worked as a Self-Employed to provide software development services to a flower shop.

I designed a POS software (Point of Sale), where sales transactions were carried out through Self-Service Terminals, which provided a new experience of automated sales to the customers.

Skills: Delphi · Firebird

Software Engineer

Defferrari Informática [01/10/2008 – 30/04/2009]

City: Novo Hamburgo | Country: Brazil | Website: http://www.defferrari.com.br/

I worked on developing the company's main product, which is Medical Management Software.

My contribution was to the design of new features and to design customized needs for the customers who were mainly physicians and hospitals.

As a result, I contributed to providing essential and tailored solutions to the customers.

Skills: Scrum · Delphi · Oracle · PL/SQ

Software Engineer

Novo Hamburgo City Hall [01/01/2007 - 27/09/2008]

City: Novo Hamburgo | Country: Brazil | Website: https://novohamburgo.rs.gov.br

Within the context of City Hall, I worked in the IT department to design new software solutions and system maintenance for the different areas of the municipality.

I contributed to designing software for Health and Public Security departments and I helped to improve the quality and availability of public services through new applications.

Skills: Delphi · MySQL · PHP · HTML · JavaScript · C# · Firebird

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Bachelor's degree, System Analysis and Development

Unisinos University - Universidade do Vale do Rio do Sinos [01/07/2012 - 30/06/2016]

City: São Leopoldo | Country: Brazil | Website: http://www.unisinos.br/

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): Portuguese

Other language(s):

English Spanish

LISTENING C1 READING C1 WRITING C1 LISTENING C1 READING C1 WRITING C1

SPOKEN PRODUCTION B2 SPOKEN INTERACTION B2 SPOKEN PRODUCTION B2 SPOKEN INTERACTION B2

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

COURSES

Courses

- Microservice Tests with Node.js and MongoDB(QANinja[qaninja.io], 2020)
- Javascript for Testers (QANinja[qaninja.io], 2020)
- React.js (Codenation [codenation.dev], 2019)
- Django 2.0 Fundamental Concepts (Udemy, 2019)
- Agile Project Manager Scrum 360, (Softwate Process Consulting in Processes, 2014)
- Java Basics (Feevale [feevale.br], 2005)
- Mobile Apps in Java J2ME (Feevale [feevale.br], 2005)
- Linux Network Installation and Administration (Feevale [feevale.br], 2003)
- Hardware and Software Maintenance and Configuration (SENAC [senac.br], 2000)

PROGRAM LANGUAGES AND TECHNOLOGIES

Program Languages and Technologies

- Expert: C#, .NET, Delphi, Object Pascal
- Great Knowledge: Azure, Docker, DDD, Microservices, MS-SQLServer(T-SQL),.NET Core, JavaScript, React.js, Node.js, RESTful APIs, HTML5, CSS3, OOP, MVC, MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite, Firebird, SVN, Git, GitHub, Scrum, Clean Code, Clean Architecture, Design Patterns, SOLID Principles
- **Good Knowledge:** Go, Kubernetes, MongoDB, PL/SQL, Python, Django, Java, React Native, Kafka, RabbitMQ, ActiveMQ, TDD, NoSQL, PHP
- Hobby/Interests: TypeScript, Deno, Firebase, AWS, Microservices, Jenkins, DevOps, gRPC